BRENDAN CORDOVA

SUMMARY

Passionate Software Developer with a focus on problem solving and results. Just over 2 years coding experience and 5 years of computer hardware experience. Leads rigorous code review sessions with students, teaching fundamentals and advanced topics. Dedicated full-stack engineer, with contract experience on a multitude of projects.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Assistant Teacher, 10/2022 - Current Colorado Technical University - Silverdale, WA

- Teaches classes of up to 80 students on modern coding languages, frameworks, and fundamentals
- Develops full-stack applications using primarily MERN and Python
- Collaborates with dev team on curriculum & learning platform
- · Runs classroom instruction on version control and cloud storage
- · Conducts hundreds of code review sessions
- Runs coding workshops: Git, GitHub, CSS, React, JavaScript, Python

Software Developer, 12/2021 - Current **Specialist in Probate -** Austin, TX

- · Work with clients to produce wireframes for website
- Develop, update, maintain, and deploy new additions to the company code as requested
- · Build internal applications
- React, JavaScript, Heroku

Software Developer & Computer Technician, 08/2020 - Current **Legacy Builds LLC -** Snohomish, WA

- Designed and deployed entire website using MongoDB, Express, React, and NodeJS, and AWS.
- Actively manages and maintains code for performance and cleanliness.
- Identifies hardware issues caused by component failures using diagnostic tools and troubleshooting.
- Customize and build computers for clients.
- · Manage repair tickets and new builds.

PROJECTS & CONTRACTS

- Portfolio: (https://nextjs13-cordova-portfolio.vercel.app/)
- Search Engine: (https://nextjs13-googleclone.vercel.app/)
- Legacy Builds, LLC: (www.legacybuildspc.com)
- Dispatch: A Full Stack Chat Application (https://github.com/cordovalegacy/Dispatch)
- IMDB Clone: (https://imdb-clone-cordovalegacy.vercel.app/)
- Specialist in Probate: (https://glacial-dawn-05023.herokuapp.com/)
- GitHub Projects: (https://github.com/cordovalegacy) 170+ repositories, 900 contributions.



CONTACT

Address: Silverdale, WA 98383

Phone: 425-802-4573

Email: cordovalegacy19@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Languages: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, CSS, HTML, JQuery, Ajax
- Frameworks: NextJS, NodeJS, Express, Flask, Bootstrap, Tailwind, SASS/SCSS, MUI
- ORM: Mongoose, Prisma, Django
- Databases: MongoDB, Firebase, MySQL (NoSQL & SQL)
- Tools: Git, Github, Heroku, Vercel, AWS EC2, AWS Route-53, VSCode, Postman, Miro, Trello

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Certificate of Graduation, Software Development, 09/2022

Coding Dojo

Black Belt Certificate of Completion, MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS, 07/2022

Coding Dojo

Certificate of Completion, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, 06/2022

Coding Dojo

Certificate of Completion, NextJS- V.13, 05/2023

Udemy